Subtitles by Nabeel Saad - nsaad@redhat.com
Hello, and welcome to the JON demo project
introduction video.. The aim of this project
is to provide a fast and easy way to build
a JON demo environment with all the
necessary features for a demo.
To dive right in, my first suggestion
is to read the README file provided
as it contains a lot of information regarding
all the aspects of the project.
You can start at the table of contents to get
a feel of the different info you can get
from that file.
Given that you are watching this video,
you have already checked the project out of
GIT and are ready to start.
So, in a terminal, I will go to
my project base directory, as you can
see mine is in within my /jon-demo-project
To start off, I will run ./scripts/main.sh
as root. Root is required as the
script may use yum, access /etc
/init.d, or other super user actions.
This will show me a splash screen with
the basics from the README that are required
to get started with the demo project.
In the background, it has created the data
folder structure necessary by the script.
Upon pressing any key, I will get a set of errors
informing me that I need to set or modify some
variables and provide appropriate product ZIPs.
Having the script install Postgres will
require an Internet connection on the first time.
So, I will do the following to setup the script:
I will modify the demo-config.properties file
under the data folder
In here, I will point the Java
Home to the  appropriate location
I will provide a local user to be used to give
ownership to all the script and demo files to that user
All the remaining modifications are optional
and mostly self explanatory. More explanation
is available in the README file.
Then I will copy enterprise ZIP files into the
appropriate locations as per the README file
and the splash screen. I
will copy the JON server ZIP.
Into the data/jon/jon-server folder
Also, all the plugins into
the appropriate sub directory
Given that I want to use bundles, I will
copy the jboss-eap-5.x ZIP file into
data/jboss, that is currently the only supported
version for bundling in the jon demo project
With other versions for bundling to come.
Now I'm ready to continue.
So I will re-run the script
And now what I see is the main
menu with some different options
Starting with some configuration options, you can
change the folder into which you'll be installing
the demo using the CD option
You'll get some options and it'll suggest the
root of  the location, as you can see, it's /opt
That can be changed in the
demo-config.properties file
You can specify a new folder or you
can choose one of the existing ones
Also, you can change the log level to get
more or less log info using the CL option.
This will mostly be useful if you are having
issues with the script and need to debug.
There's an option to create bundles separately from the
JON demo installation as long as you have provided the
JBoss EAP zip and you have Ant installed on your system
Of course, this can be executed as part of the demo install
but can also be run separately to use the bundles for
other purposes.
There are other options that you can read more about
in the README file and some only available in debug mode.
So moving on to the heart of the script, I will input
ID to start the demo installation. First thing that'll
happen is a check for postgres on the filesystem,
by checking for a service file in /etc/init.d and
and then it'll check if you've previously
installed postgres via the script variables
If neither are the case, as we see now, it'll provide you
a list of the most recent version numbers for your particular
OS and architecture of postgres that you can install.
Once you select the version, the first question is
if you want to install the bundles. I will go
ahead and choose the version 9.1 as my postgres.
So as you can see, the next question is if I want to
install the bundles.  At this point I will say "yes"
to use all the available features of the demo, but
you can choose not to install them if you so desire.
Given that we are installing the bundles, we get to specify
how many JBoss servers we want to deploy via the JON bundles
0 for no servers, or up to 10 local instances.
I'll choose one at the moment.
The next option is to select the version of JON
to be installed, this will depend on the ZIPs you
have provided in the data/jon/jon-server.x.x.x folder.
Again, I will choose the only option that's
available to me right now, providing the number 1.
Once you choose that, the process will run and deploy
everything. As it runs, I will explain some of the things
taking place. First, it'll install postgres using yum.
This will install the server and the necessary libraries,
initialise the database, and update the configuration.
Once it completes, it will create an rhqadmin user
with default credentials along with an rhq database
to be used by the JON server.
If at a later point in time, you were to run the install
script or if you already had postgres and the rhq database
you'll be asked for a name for the
database to be created by the script
Once postgres has been set up properly, the bundles will
be built by calling the Ant sub project for building the
bundles. That runs in parallel to the build, and
the script continues to extract the JON ZIP to the
install location with updates to configuration
as necessary to allow for auto-installation.
This script will also copy patches and plugins,
deploy them to the data folder for that version
of JON. Please ensure you use compatible versions
of the patches and plugins that work with the JON
version that you are using.
Then the JON server will be started up and it'll
run thru the initial install setup silently
In the meantime, the JON agent will be deployed
locally with all discovery scan periods set to
30 seconds and started as a service.
Also the CLI tool will be deployed into
the demo install under a JON-TOOLS directory
Finally, using the CLI the script will import
the local server into JON, add it to a group
and upload and deploy the JON bundles
depending on your previous answers.
Now bear in mind that the
bundle setup is as follows -
and you can see more about this in the README file.
There is a common bundle that holds the top-
level JBoss folders such as conf, bin, lib, etc...
And this is called the common bundle.
Then, another bundle that installs the JBoss
profile with a symbolic link from the common/server
directory.  These nodes will be installed with
port numbers increasing incrementally
by 100 for each server instance installed.
Each instance is started as part of the
bundle deployment, and added as a service under
/etc/init.d directory.
Finally, there's a dvd-store
application deployed to each node.
Once all the bundle deployments
complete, then the script is finished
We'll give the JON server
setup a few moments to complete
And then, the remaining part left for
this script will be to deploy the bundles
In the meantime, we can access
the JON server once it's ready.
The (default) credentials are rhqadmin/rhqadmin,
as is defined in the installation manual for JON
Once the agent connects to the server and sends
it's first availability report, informing it of
any resources that are available on the local machine
Then the script will setup the JON server to
have a new group called Linux-Platforms, it will
auto-import any resources - which will be the
local platform - and it will add the local platform
into that group.
Once it's done that, it will install the bundles
into the JON server.  So there are three bundles
that have been created and exist under data/
bundles and they get uploaded into the system.
And having chosen to deploy a JBoss server, at this
point, we are deploying only one.  We can see the
deployments being invoked
As part of the bundle deployment, the JBoss server
that is deployed will get started up, so that it
can get picked up by the JON server
after a discovery and an availability scan
And as you can see, the EAP server itself
is being imported into the JON server
Finally, some configuration is done to the
connection settings so that JON can connect to
the EAP server. And that's the script complete
in 7 minutes and 22 seconds from start to finish.
If you were to do this without postgres you might
be looking at anywhere between 4 to 5 minutes
Of course depending on your machine.
(Mine is i7 quad-core, 8GB RAM)
So, that is the completion of the script itself.
Now, if I come back to the JON server very quickly.
We've logged into the JON server to
see the setup completed by the script.
Under "Inventory", we can see the local platform that
has been imported under "Servers - Top Level Platforms"
Then, under "Compatible Groups", we can see the
Linux-Platform group that has been created
Containing, under the "Inventory"
tab, the local server as a member.
Finally, going to the "Bundles" tab, we can see
the bundles that have been uploaded into JON
The destinations, and the live
deployments that have taken place.
That's the current setup as it ends up at this
point in time. Please refer to the README file
for updates on new features for this project.
Hope you found this useful.  Please do feel free
to contact me for any help relating to the script
Via my contact details in the README file.
Thanks for watching (nsaad@redhat.com)
Nabeel Saad - nsaad@redhat.com